Yan Ying
يان ينغ
Mother, where are you going?
أمي ، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Wake up!
استيقظ!
-Do something. -Boss Jin, it's
-قم بعمل ما.  -بوس جين ، إنه
okay. Yan Ying is fine.
حسنا.  يان ينغ بخير.
Wake up Yan Ying,
استيقظ يان ينغ ،
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Boss Jin,
بوس جين ،
Pan Jun and the others are here.
بان جون والآخرون هنا.
Tell them to wait for me at Hengfeng Hotel.
أخبرهم أن ينتظروني في فندق Hengfeng.
Don't come to my office.
لا تأتي إلى مكتبي.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
and,
و،
Keep a close eye on Fengchen Jun,
راقب عن كثب Fengchen Jun ،
see what he's up to,
انظر ماذا يفعل ،
Yes.
نعم.
Boss Jin,
بوس جين ،
otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
Let's inject him with painkillers.
لنحقنه بالمسكنات.
You can't use it.
لا يمكنك استخدامه.
Yan Ying has to get through this.
يجب على يان ينغ تجاوز هذا.
I'm going to get him off Fengchen Jun's medication,
سأخرجه من دواء Fengchen Jun ،
otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
He'll be like me
سيكون مثلي
for 20 years,
لمدة 20 عاما،
They all rely on other people's drugs to maintain their lives.
يعتمدون جميعًا على أدوية الآخرين للحفاظ على حياتهم.
Take your gun
خذ بندقيتك
and stand at the door.
والوقوف عند الباب.
No matter what Yan Ying calls you,
بغض النظر عما يدعوك يان ينغ ،
no one is allowed to come in and help him.
لا يسمح لأحد بالدخول ومساعدته.
Including yourself.
بما فيهم نفسك.
Help me!
ساعدني!
Sister, help me,
أختي ، ساعدني ،
Yes.
نعم.
Remember,
يتذكر،
those who disobey the order,
أولئك الذين يخالفون الأمر ،
Kill them on sight.
اقتلهم على مرمى البصر.
Mr. Jin.
السيد جين.
What can I do for you?
ما الذي يمكنني أن أفعله من أجلك؟
The chief of the Xue family wants to ask you
يريد رئيس عائلة Xue أن يسألك
to help save the young master of the Xue family,
للمساعدة في إنقاذ السيد الشاب لعائلة Xue ،
You really want something from me.
أنت حقا تريد شيئا مني.
That's why you brought Yan Yun
لهذا السبب أحضرت يان يون
to threaten me, right?
لتهديدي ، أليس كذلك؟
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
They are my friends.
انهم اصدقائي.
There's no need to do that.
ليس هناك حاجة للقيام بذلك.
Besides,
بجانب،
a mother who abandoned her own child
أم تخلت عن طفلها
for more than 20 years,
لأكثر من 20 عامًا ،
Are you worried about my safety?
هل أنت قلق على سلامتي؟
When the Zerg was forced by Lord He,
عندما أجبر الرب الزرج ،
the Zerg treasure was what your father and daughter
كنز الزرج هو ما كان والدك وابنتك
always wanted.
يريد دائما.
The bloody battle in Bamen Mountain was also caused by you.
أنت أيضًا سبب المعركة الدامية في جبل بامين.
You're the one who abandoned my father
أنت من تخلت عن والدي
and caused his illness for more than ten years,
وتسبب في مرضه لأكثر من عشر سنوات ،
Yan Ying and I,
يان ينغ وأنا ،
you were the one who had no parents since we were little,
كنت من لم يكن لديك أبوين منذ أن كنا صغارًا ،
The one who killed Second Grandpa
الشخص الذي قتل الجد الثاني
and Senior Pan Shujin,
وكبير بان شوجين ،
It's still you.
مازلت أنت هو أنت.
Did Ouyang Leiyun tell you all this?
هل أخبرك أويانغ ليون بكل هذا؟
You don't have the right to call me grandpa's name.
ليس لديك الحق في مناداتي باسم جدي.
My grandfather is right,
جدي على حق
you are the traitor of Ouyang Family.
أنت خائن عائلة أويانغ.
You don't deserve to be our mother.
أنت لا تستحقين أن تكوني أمنا.
Clan Leader Xue promised,
وعد زعيم العشيرة Xue ،
he is willing to reveal the truth 24 years ago.
إنه على استعداد لكشف الحقيقة منذ 24 عامًا.
I'll clear your name.
سوف امسح اسمك.
Mr. Jin,
السيد جين ،
Yan Ying can't hold on any longer.
لم يعد بإمكان يان ينغ الصمود أكثر من ذلك.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Don't move! Don't move!
لا تتحرك!  لا تتحرك!
Yan Ying, Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ، يان ينغ ،
take me home.
خذنى إلى المنزل.
I have a home,
لدي منزل
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Put the gun down!
ضع المسدس ارضا!
Why did you leave me alone?
لماذا تركتني وحدي؟
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
stay away.
ابق بعيدا.
Don't touch me! Get up!
لا تلمسني!  استيقظ!
Get up.
استيقظ.
Yan Ying, put the gun down. Yan Ying
يان ينغ ، أنزل المسدس.  يان ينغ
Sis,
الاخت ،
When Grandpa hit me,
عندما ضربني جدي ،
why did you...?
لماذا فعلت...؟
Why did you leave me alone?
لماذا تركتني وحدي؟
I didn't. Put the gun down.
لم أكن.  ضع المسدس ارضا.
It hurts.
هذا مؤلم.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I've only had my sister since I was a child.
لم يكن لدي سوى أختي منذ أن كنت طفلة.
No father,
لا أب،
no mother,
ولا أم،
Why did you leave me alone?
لماذا تركتني وحدي؟
Yan Ying
يان ينغ
Put the gun down Yan Ying
ضع المسدس أسفل يان ينغ
doesn't have a father,
ليس لديه أب
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
can you give me the gun?
هل تستطيع أن تعطيني البندقية؟
Give me the gun.
أعطني البندقية.
Mother.
الأم.
Why don't you want me?
لماذا لا تريدني
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
why?
لماذا ا؟
Stand up.
الوقوف.
Get up and you don't care about me.
انهض وأنت لا تهتم بي.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
you don't care about me.
أنت لا تهتم بي.
Boss Jin,
بوس جين ،
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Maybe I can save him.
ربما يمكنني إنقاذه.
It's not getting any better.
لا يتحسن الوضع.
Do you have any other way?
هل لديك طريقة أخرى؟
I did everything I could.
فعلت كل ما بوسعي.
Now it's about his willpower,
الآن يتعلق الأمر بقوة إرادته ،
so I can't help you with that.
لذلك لا يمكنني مساعدتك في ذلك.
Xiao'e, don't go.
Xiao'e ، لا تذهب.
You're a Zerg, too.
أنت زرج أيضًا.
No secrets.
لا اسرار.
Don't you like to drink?
ألا تحب أن تشرب؟
Let's just have a drink today.
دعونا فقط نشرب اليوم.
First of all,
أولاً،
the deaths of Jin Wu Yi, Pan Pu
وفاة جين وو يي ، بان بو
and Ouyang Lei Huo have nothing to do with me.
و Ouyang Lei Huo ليس لديهم أي علاقة بي.
The Yaxin Club is complicated,
نادي Yaxin معقد ،
so I don't need to explain it to you.
لذلك لست بحاجة إلى شرح ذلك لك.
Secondly,
ثانيًا،
I did go to Mount Fuzhou.
لقد ذهبت إلى جبل فوتشو.
But I did it for you, for Yan Ying,
لكنني فعلت ذلك من أجلك ، من أجل يان ينغ ،
and for the rest,
وللباقي ،
It was all done by Yin and Yang,
كل ذلك قام به "يين" و "يانغ" ،
and it has nothing to do with me.
ولا علاقة لي به.
I'll clear myself up.
سوف أبرئ نفسي.
Have a clear conscience.
ارتاح الضمير.
Then what exactly does Clan Leader Xue
ثم ماذا يفعل Clan Leader Xue بالضبط
mean by what he asked me to do?
يعني بما طلب مني أن أفعل؟
24 years ago,
قبل 24 عاما ،
my father,
والدى،
It's a Zerg.
إنه Zerg.
Lord He of the Qing court, who hates you so much.
اللورد هو من بلاط تشينغ ، الذي يكرهك كثيرًا.
Accidentally got a Luo Shi lost by Xue clan
حصلت عن طريق الخطأ على لوه شي فقدته عشيرة Xue
at the end of Ming Dynasty,
في نهاية عهد أسرة مينج ،
He was ordered to be escorted by soldiers.
وأمر بأن يرافقه جنود.
Gather the Zerg in Mount Ba Men.
اجمعوا الزرج في جبل با من.
Trying to open the treasure.
تحاول فتح الكنز.
But who ever thought,
ولكن من كان يظن ،
Xue Gui, the chief priest of Xue clan,
Xue Gui ، الكاهن الرئيسي لعشيرة Xue ،
But the river stone he took out is fake.
لكن حجر النهر الذي أخرجه مزيف.
It caused Shi Shiyu, a gentleman in the water system,
تسبب في شي شيو ، رجل نبيل في نظام المياه ،
to come out crazily and kill innocent people indiscriminately.
للخروج بجنون وقتل الأبرياء دون تمييز.
As for the rest,
أما الباقي ،
you must have heard about it many times.
لا بد أنك سمعت عنها مرات عديدة.
But my grandpa said,
لكن جدي قال ،
Luo Shi is the fake one.
لوه شي هو المزيف.
Your grandpa,
جدك ،
your grandpa has always been arrogant,
كان جدك متعجرفًا دائمًا ،
How could he dare to face the truth?
كيف يجرؤ على مواجهة الحقيقة؟
Fortunately, Xue Gui is willing to testify for me.
لحسن الحظ ، Xue Gui على استعداد للشهادة لي.
Go on.
تابع.
Back then, Xue Gui insisted that
في ذلك الوقت ، أصر Xue Gui على ذلك
my father's rock was fake.
كانت صخرة والدي مزيفة.
The Zerg
الزرج
are united with Xiang Laixu,
متحدون مع Xiang Laixu ،
There has never been a traitor.
لم يكن هناك خائن قط.
So,
لذا،
they threw all their hatred
ألقوا كل حقدهم
towards my father on me.
تجاه أبي.
He put a thousand insects on me and killed me.
وضع عليّ ألف حشرة وقتلني.
Your grandpa,
جدك ،
with his face of putting righteousness above family loyalty,
بوجهه الذي يضع البر فوق ولاء الأسرة ،
I still remember,
مازلت اتذكر،
the Thousand Insects Devouring Bone Poison,
ألف حشرة تلتهم سم العظام ،
In the past 24 years,
في الـ 24 سنة الماضية ،
he has been torturing me every night.
كان يعذبني كل ليلة.
Fortunately, Xue Gui has a conscience,
لحسن الحظ ، لدى Xue Gui ضمير ،
and after what happened,
وبعد ما حدث
He blamed himself.
ألقى باللوم على نفسه.
ashamed and uneasy
بالخجل وعدم الارتياح
Save me in time.
أنقذني في الوقت المناسب.
You asked a doctor to treat me again.
طلبت من طبيب أن يعالجني مرة أخرى.
That's how I saved my life.
هكذا أنقذت حياتي.
Otherwise, I would have died.
خلاف ذلك ، كنت سأموت.
So,
لذا،
you have to seek revenge on Grandpa.
عليك أن تنتقم من جدي.
If this is you,
إذا كان هذا أنت ،
can you not take revenge?
لا يمكنك الانتقام؟
I hope you can call me mom.
آمل أن تتمكن من الاتصال بي أمي.
I hope you and Yan Ying
أتمنى لك ويان ينغ
can follow me out of here and back to Japan,
يمكن أن يتبعني من هنا والعودة إلى اليابان ،
But I won't force you.
لكنني لن أجبرك.
You can't force me.
لا يمكنك إجباري.
When did you two find out?
متى اكتشفتا؟
Just like you.
مثلك تماما.
Xue Gui told us
أخبرنا Xue Gui
in the Xue family.
في عائلة Xue.
It's no different from
لا يختلف عن
what your mother and Jin Sumei said.
ما قالته والدتك وجين سومي.
Well
نحن سوف
Love and hate in this world,
الحب والكراهية في هذا العالم ،
it's hard to part with each other.
من الصعب أن تنفصل عن بعضها البعض.
I can't tell right from wrong.
لا أستطيع التمييز بين الصواب والخطأ.
So,
لذا،
don't take it too seriously.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد.
As for the pursuit of Mount Fuzhou,
أما عن مطاردة جبل فوتشو ،
it must be Fengchen Jun's Yin-Yang Road
يجب أن يكون طريق Fengchen Jun's Yin-Yang
and Matsui Shangyuan,
وماتسوي شانغيوان ،
The death of your second grandfather,
وفاة جدك الثاني
is not directly related to Boss Jin,
ليس له علاقة مباشرة بـ Boss Jin ،
I just hope,
أنا فقط أتمنى،
you won't be too upset and sad.
لن تكون منزعجًا وحزينًا جدًا.
Be nice to your mother.
كن لطيفا مع والدتك.
It's easy to say.
من السهل القول.
Didn't you threaten
ألم تهدد
to take revenge,
ينتقم،
Aren't you going to let anyone of the Zerg go?
ألن تدع أحداً من الزرج يذهب؟
You're right.
أنت على حق.
Over the past 20 years,
على مدار العشرين عامًا الماضية ،
in my life, apart from revenge,
في حياتي عدا الانتقام
I can't see anything else.
لا أستطيع رؤية أي شيء آخر.
But you're the only one who has experienced it.
لكنك الوحيد الذي اختبر ذلك.
Then you will know
ثم ستعرف
how to cherish it,
كيف نعتز به ،
How important it is.
ما مدى أهمية ذلك.
Listen to me or not.
استمع لي ام لا
I don't mean to force you.
لا أقصد إجبارك.
No, I'm not lying.
لا ، أنا لا أكذب.
Mei'er is innocent,
مئير بريء
Luo Shi is the real Luo Shi,
لو شي هو لوه شي الحقيقي ،
Let me prove it to you.
دعني أثبت لك ذلك.
Don't go.
لا تذهب.
Grandpa told me,
قال لي جدي ،
there's a lunatic in there.
هناك مجنون هناك.
He's a sinner of Ouyang's family.
إنه خاطئ من عائلة أويانغ.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
why are you here? Yan Ying
لماذا أنت هنا؟  يان ينغ
Father,
أب،
What does Her Highness look like?
كيف تبدو صاحبة السمو؟
When can I see her?
متى يمكنني رؤيتها؟
Grow up quickly.
يكبر بسرعة.
I'll take you to see my mother when you grow up.
سآخذك لرؤية والدتي عندما تكبر.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
Did you go to find that lunatic?
هل ذهبت لتجد ذلك المجنون؟
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Grandpa,
الجد
grandpa, stop hitting me.
جدي ، توقف عن ضربي.
Did you go to find that lunatic?
هل ذهبت لتجد ذلك المجنون؟
Grandpa, stop beating him.
جدي ، توقف عن ضربه.
Get out of the way!
ابتعد عن الطريق!
Mother
الأم
It can't be quiet.
لا يمكن أن تكون هادئة.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Yan Ying, Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ، يان ينغ ،
What a loser. You have no memory.
يا لك من فاشل.  ليس لديك ذاكرة.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
Are you going or not?
هل انت ذاهب ام لا؟
Tell me,
أخبرني،
are you going or not?
انت ذاهب ام لا
Yan Ying.
يان ينغ.
I was wrong.
لقد كنت مخطئ.
I was wrong. I was wrong.
لقد كنت مخطئ.  لقد كنت مخطئ.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
you're right.
أنت على حق.
Don't punish yourself
لا تعاقب نفسك
for other people's mistakes, okay?
لأخطاء الآخرين ، حسنًا؟
Yan Ying.
يان ينغ.
He really doesn't treat me as an outsider.
إنه حقًا لا يعاملني كغريب.
Mother,
الأم،
Dr. Pan has checked your pulse,
قام دكتور بان بفحص نبضك ،
and he said you're fine.
وقال إنك بخير.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
I feel much better.
أشعر أفضل بكثير.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'm sorry
أنا آسف
I didn't take good care of you.
لم أعتني بك جيدًا.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
He did sleep well.
لقد نام جيدا.
Welcome back.
مرحبًا بعودتك.
My dear friend,
صديقي العزيز،
I'm not here to fight.
لست هنا للقتال.
if
لو
You don't want Ziwu and Young Master Xue to die?
ألا تريد أن يموت Ziwu و Young Master Xue؟
So on the day of beginning of spring,
لذلك في يوم بداية الربيع ،
all of you,
كلكم،
Come to me at the Thousand Worm Altar.
تعال إلي عند مذبح الألف دودة.
Okay.
تمام.
See you in beginning of spring.
نراكم في بداية الربيع.
When the time comes for Uncle Pan's hatred of Qiu Ziwu,
عندما يحين وقت كراهية العم بان لـ Qiu Ziwu ،
I'll settle it with you.
سوف أقوم بتسوية الأمر معك.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
I've always been very interested in you.
لطالما كنت مهتمًا جدًا بك.
Pneumonic Plague,
طاعون رئوي،
is one of my most satisfying works
هو واحد من أكثر أعمالي إرضاءً
in recent years.
فى السنوات الاخيرة.
I didn't expect you to be so good.
لم أكن أتوقع أن تكون جيدًا جدًا.
Do you know that
هل تعرف أن
you're making me unhappy.
أنت تجعلني غير سعيد.
But the new work
لكن العمل الجديد
is more interesting than Pneumonic Plague.
أكثر إثارة للاهتمام من الطاعون الرئوي.
Do you know where this inspiration comes from?
هل تعرف من أين يأتي هذا الإلهام؟
The inspiration comes from
الإلهام يأتي من
your five families,
عائلاتك الخمس ،
In the war 24 years ago,
في الحرب قبل 24 عامًا ،
Mount Ba Men,
ماونت با مين
What a nice place.
يا له من مكان جميل.
Then let's go to the Thousand Worm Altar.
ثم دعنا نذهب إلى مذبح الألف دودة.
See you there.
اراك هناك.
I won't
أنا لن
see you.
أرك لاحقًا.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Go to Xue Family's settlement and unite Xue Zifeng
انتقل إلى تسوية Xue Family وتوحد Xue Zifeng
to eliminate Yin and Yang Dao.
للقضاء على يين ويانغ داو.
This way, please.
من هنا لو سمحت.
The Thousand Worm Sacrifice,
ذبيحة الدودة الألف ،
is the biggest festival of Xue's Group.
هو أكبر مهرجان لمجموعة Xue.
Everyone began to prepare
بدأ الجميع في الاستعداد
tributes and talismans months in advance.
التحية والتعويذات بأشهر مقدما.
By the beginning of spring,
بحلول بداية الربيع ،
every family will send tributes
كل عائلة سترسل تحية
to the altar of thousands of insects,
إلى مذبح آلاف الحشرات ،
To commemorate the deceased relatives, friends and ancestors,
تخليدًا لذكرى الأقارب والأصدقاء والأجداد المتوفين ،
in order to bless us
ليباركنا
with a bumper harvest and good weather in the coming year.
مع حصاد وفير وطقس جيد في العام المقبل.
Well.
نحن سوف.
Didn't you tell the hunters that
ألم تخبر الصيادين بذلك
we're going to fight with the Yin and Yang Daos?
نحن ذاهبون للقتال مع يين ويانغ داوس؟
This decisive battle is extraordinary.
هذه المعركة الحاسمة غير عادية.
Chief Priest doesn't want to implicate innocent people.
رئيس الكهنة لا يريد توريط الأبرياء.
So the news hasn't been announced yet.
لذلك لم يتم الإعلان عن الأخبار بعد.
However,
لكن،
we Xue clan have always been brave and fearless,
نحن عشيرة Xue كنا دائمًا شجعانًا وخائفين ،
And we are fully prepared.
ونحن على استعداد تام.
To prevent miasma,
للوقاية من الميا ،
we went up the mountain a month ago to collect herbs,
صعدنا الجبل قبل شهر لجمع الأعشاب ،
We will definitely win this battle.
سوف نفوز بالتأكيد في هذه المعركة.
What's with the miasma?
ما هو المستحضر؟
After the severe cold,
بعد البرد القارس ،
the Thousand Worm Altar will breed miasma.
سوف يولد مذبح الألف دودة المستنقعات.
The whole altar will be filled
يملأ المذبح كله
until beginning of spring.
حتى بداية الربيع.
Except for our people,
باستثناء شعبنا ،
most outsiders will be choked out.
سيتم خنق معظم الغرباء.
How about
ماذا عن
this? Take Miaomiao to the witch doctor's mother-in-law first.
هذه؟  اصطحب مياومياو إلى حمات الطبيب الساحر أولاً.
I'm going to find some big pots.
سأجد بعض الأواني الكبيرة.
Why are you looking for big pots?
لماذا تبحث عن قدور كبيرة؟
You'll find out in a while.
سوف تكتشف ذلك بعد قليل.
Let's go this way.
دعنا نذهب بهذه الطريقة.
Granny
الجدة
All the herbs are here.
كل الأعشاب هنا.
It's all prepared according to the amount in previous years.
كل شيء معدة حسب الكمية في السنوات السابقة.
Nothing will go wrong.
لن يحدث شيء خطأ.
Madam,
سيدتي،
this year's Thousand Worm Sacrifice
أضحية الألف دودة هذا العام
Old Clan Leader will invite some distinguished guests to join us,
سيدعو Old Clan Leader بعض الضيوف المميزين للانضمام إلينا ،
Plus,
زائد،
there are more people and soldiers in our whole settlement
هناك المزيد من الناس والجنود في مستوطنتنا بأكملها
than in previous years.
مما كانت عليه في السنوات السابقة.
I'm afraid that's not enough.
أخشى أن هذا لا يكفي.
Since it's a distinguished guest invited by Clan Leader,
نظرًا لكونه ضيفًا مميزًا تمت دعوته من قِبل زعيم القبيلة ،
I'll prepare something for you.
سأجهز لك شيئا.
This is more tiring than buying new year's goods.
هذا متعب أكثر من شراء سلع العام الجديد.
Just one basin.
مجرد حوض واحد.
They were sent to the compound.
تم إرسالهم إلى المجمع.
Do you still draw the spell of Xue clan?
هل مازلت ترسم تعويذة عشيرة Xue؟
Draw,
رسم،
We have to get everything ready.
علينا تجهيز كل شيء.
I'm sure it's safe,
أنا متأكد من أنها آمنة ،
so I can use
حتى أتمكن من استخدامها
these thousand insects during the sacrifice.
هذه الألف حشرة أثناء الذبيحة.
If Yin and Yang insist on hosting the Thousand Worm Sacrifice,
إذا أصر يين ويانغ على استضافة ذبيحة الألف دودة ،
we can't afford to lose our share, right?
لا يمكننا تحمل خسارة حصتنا ، أليس كذلك؟
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
How did the Thousand Worm Sacrifice become the host of Yin and Yang?
كيف أصبحت ذبيحة الألف دودة مضيفة لـ Yin و Yang؟
Isn't this nonsense?
أليس هذا هراء؟
We're family members.
نحن أفراد العائلة.
Where's Chief Priest?
أين رئيس الكهنة؟
Why do you want an outsider to preside over it?
لماذا تريد من الخارج أن يرأسها؟
Everyone, tell me,
أخبرني الجميع ،
who will offer our sacrifice?
من سيقدم تضحياتنا؟
The Thousand Worm Sacrifice is our ancestor worship ceremony,
ذبيحة الألف دودة هي مراسم عبادة أسلافنا ،
how can we let the Yin and Yang Daos occupy the altar?
كيف يمكننا ترك يين ويانغ داوس يحتلان المذبح؟
We can't let them go.
لا يمكننا السماح لهم بالرحيل.
That's our place.
هذا مكاننا.
Don't worry. Listen to me first.
لا تقلق.  استمع إلي أولا.
Our sacrifice.
تضحيتنا.
If we ask Clan Leader Xue to deliver it in person,
إذا طلبنا من Clan Leader Xue تسليمها شخصيًا ،
we can't let outsiders
لا يمكننا السماح للغرباء
defile our altar offerings.
تنجس قرابين مذبحنا.
If that's the case,
إذا كان هذا هو الحال،
we can't do
لا نستطيع أن نفعل
it ourselves.
ذلك بأنفسنا.
Beginning of spring is too dangerous.
بداية الربيع خطيرة للغاية.
None of you can go.
لا أحد منكم يستطيع الذهاب.
Yin-Yang Road kidnapped Young Master,
طريق Yin-Yang خطف السيد الشاب ،
we did this
فعلنا هذا
to counter Yin-Yang Road.
لمواجهة طريق Yin-Yang.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Young Master, Young Master is in their hands.
السيد الشاب ، السيد الشاب في أيديهم.
Yin and Yang do have a stubborn heart.
يين ويانغ لديهما قلب عنيد.
We need to save Young Master.
نحن بحاجة لإنقاذ السيد الشاب.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
On the day of beginning of spring,
في يوم بداية الربيع ،
At the Thousand Worm Altar,
عند مذبح الألف دودة ،
we'll face the Yin and Yang Daos head-on,
سنواجه يين ويانغ داوس وجهاً لوجه ،
So I hope everyone won't leave the house.
لذلك آمل ألا يغادر الجميع المنزل.
Don't go to the sacrifice, okay?
لا تذهب إلى التضحية ، حسناً؟
Who will deliver this year's tribute?
من الذي سيلقي التكريم هذا العام؟
Yes.
نعم.
What about the tribute we prepared?
ماذا عن الجزية التي أعددناها؟
Our gods,
آلهتنا ،
our relatives and ancestors must not be neglected.
يجب عدم إهمال أقاربنا وأجدادنا.
Yes, don't neglect it.
نعم ، لا تهملها.
I'll deliver it for everyone, okay?
سأقوم بتسليمها للجميع ، حسنًا؟
I'll send all the offerings you've prepared
سأرسل كل العروض التي أعددتها
to the altar.
الى المذبح.
I will also pray to the gods of the sun and moon.
كما سأصلي لآلهة الشمس والقمر.
Bless our Xue clan,
يبارك عشيرة Xue لدينا ،
and bless us
وبارك فينا
to save Young Master Xue back.
لإنقاذ Young Master Xue مرة أخرى.
Who is it?
من هذا؟
I know.
أنا أعرف.
The annual Thousand Worms Sacrifice,
ذبيحة الألف دودة السنوية ،
is very important to everyone.
مهم جدًا للجميع.
Me
أنا
As a descendant of the Floral Department,
بصفته سليل قسم الأزهار ،
my father,
والدى،
My father, Pan Yingxuan, once treated you.
والدي ، بان ينغشوان ، عاملك مرة.
So I will bring all my feelings
لذلك سوف أحمل كل مشاعري
to the God of Sun and Moon.
لإله الشمس والقمر.
I also hope you can trust me.
آمل أيضًا أن تثق بي.
Trust me, a descendant of the Floral Clan.
صدقني ، سليل عشيرة الأزهار.
Mr. Pan,
السيد بان ،
our tribute for this year,
تكريمنا لهذا العام ،
I'll leave it all to you.
سأترك كل شيء لك.
Please give it to you.
من فضلك أعطه لك.
Time to eat.
وقت الطعام.
You.
أنت.
As long as you help us save Ziwu and his master,
طالما أنك تساعدنا في إنقاذ Ziwu وسيده ،
I'll call you mother.
سأتصل بك يا أمي.
If you don't help me,
إذا لم تساعدني ،
I don't seem
لا يبدو
to want to hear you call me mother.
لأريد أن أسمعك تناديني يا أمي.
Just leave it here after dinner.
فقط اتركه هنا بعد العشاء.
Someone will clean it up.
شخص ما سوف ينظفها.
I need to go out.
أحتاج الى الخروج.
I'll come back to see you later.
سأعود لرؤيتك لاحقا.
The longest piece of green silk is missing from your bag,
أطول قطعة من الحرير الأخضر مفقودة من حقيبتك ،
I saw your father use it once,
رأيت والدك يستخدمه مرة واحدة
That's the secret treasure of our wood system,
هذا هو الكنز السري لنظامنا الخشبي ،
Spirit Piercing Needle. Are you sure
إبرة ثقب الروح.  هل أنت واثق
you've seen that
لقد رأيت ذلك
I was also infected during the late plague.
لقد أصبت أيضًا أثناء الطاعون المتأخر.
Young Master and Old Clan Leader
السيد الشاب وزعيم العشيرة القديم
forced me to take the medicine your father gave me,
أجبرني على تناول الدواء الذي أعطاني إياه والدك ،
But at that time, both sides of my shoulders were red and swollen,
ولكن في ذلك الوقت ، كان وجهي كتفي حمراء ومنتفخة ،
and I couldn't lift my bow or shoot an arrow.
ولم أتمكن من رفع قوسي أو إطلاق سهم.
Your father told me it's plague
أخبرني والدك أنه طاعون
sequelae arthralgia syndrome,
متلازمة آلام المفاصل ،
If you don't treat him,
إذا لم تعامله ،
your arms will be ruined.
سوف تدمر ذراعيك.
He retired everyone.
تقاعد الجميع.
We were the only ones left in the woodshed.
كنا الوحيدين الذين بقوا في مخزن الحطب.
No matter how much I refused,
مهما رفضت ،
he still took out the longest Spiritual Pivot Needle,
لا يزال يأخذ أطول إبرة محورية روحية ،
Your father told me,
قال لي والدك ،
all the Qingsi in the Department of Wood have saved people.
لقد أنقذ كل Qingsi في قسم الخشب الناس.
He killed someone too.
لقد قتل شخصًا أيضًا.
Only this Green Silk of Spiritual Pivot,
فقط هذا الحرير الأخضر للمحور الروحي ،
can only be saved,
يمكن حفظها فقط ،
Don't kill him!
لا تقتله!
The funny thing is,
الشيء المضحك هو
Lingshu Qingsi, the secret treasure of your wood system,
Lingshu Qingsi ، الكنز السري لنظامك الخشبي ،
saved these two arms.
أنقذ هذين الذراعين.
He killed countless people,
لقد قتل عددًا لا يحصى من الناس ،
and your father said,
وقال والدك
It's hard to tell right from wrong, good from evil,
من الصعب التمييز بين الصواب والخطأ ، والخير من الشر ،
and he never cares,
ولا يهتم أبدًا ،
He only cares about his perseverance
إنه يهتم فقط بمثابرته
and justice.
والعدالة.
Young Master Xue,
السيد الشاب شيويه ،
I've always been tired of killing,
لطالما سئمت القتل ،
But this time,
لكن هذه المرة ،
in order to solve the mystery of the Zerg treasure,
من أجل حل لغز كنز الزرق ،
Let me climb to the peak of medical research.
اسمحوا لي أن أصعد إلى ذروة البحث الطبي.
I'm afraid the Xue family
أخشى عائلة Xue
will suffer.
سيعاني.
The shotguns and crossbows of the Xue family,
البنادق والأقواس من عائلة Xue ،
not only protect the Xue family,
ليس فقط حماية عائلة Xue ،
And protect the Zerg.
وتحمي الزرج.
Young Master Xue, you're wrong again.
السيد الصغير شيويه ، أنت مخطئ مرة أخرى.
The era of cold weapons has passed.
لقد ولى عصر الأسلحة الباردة.
In the future,
فى المستقبل،
he'll be competing with a steel gun,
سوف يتنافس مع مسدس فولاذي ،
The Zerg treasure can get it.
كنز الزرج يمكنه الحصول عليه.
It's better than
انها أفضل من
putting it
وضعه
in an unknown world.
في عالم مجهول.
The Xue family guards He Luoshi,
تحرس عائلة شيويه هي لوشي ،
relying on the trust of the Zerg.
معتمدين على ثقة الزرج.
You only want to seize the treasure,
أنت فقط تريد الاستيلاء على الكنز ،
and the name of injustice has been confirmed.
وتأكد اسم الظلم.
No matter how the world changes,
مهما تغير العالم ،
the crossbow of our Xue family,
القوس والنشاب لعائلة Xue لدينا ،
Always point to the unjust.
دائما أشر إلى الظالم.
Before the treasure came out,
قبل أن يخرج الكنز ،
the Far East fell into a warlord battle,
سقط الشرق الأقصى في معركة أمراء الحرب ،
The people are not living well.
الناس لا يعيشون بشكل جيد.
There is a lot of sorrow everywhere,
هناك الكثير من الحزن في كل مكان ،
Yes
نعم
Pan Jun and his party,
بان جون وحزبه ،
they call themselves the teachers of justice,
يسمون أنفسهم معلمي العدل ،
It's a pity that they … They showed their
إنه لأمر مؤسف أنهم ... أظهروا
courage,
شجاعة،
They didn't look at the pattern in the past century,
لم ينظروا إلى النمط السائد في القرن الماضي ،
look at me, Fengchen Jun,
انظر إلي ، Fengchen Jun ،
In order to study the Zerg treasure,
من أجل دراسة كنز الزرج ،
I did my best,
قمت بأفضل ما عندي،
I just want to lift its veil.
أنا فقط أريد أن أرفع حجابها.
I'll let these muddy and short-sighted people have a look.
سأترك هؤلاء الأشخاص الموحلين وقصير النظر يلقون نظرة.
What do you mean
ماذا تقصد
by "material charm"?
بواسطة "سحر المواد"؟
medicine
دواء
So many.
كثير جدا.
You're no match for Pan Jun.
أنت لا تتطابق مع Pan Jun.
He can let go of his personal grudges
يمكنه التخلي عن ضغائنه الشخصية
and be righteous.
وكونوا صالحين.
He knows that,
لأنه يعلم أن،
but you'll never understand.
لكنك لن تفهم أبدًا.
Look at
ينظر الى
this world.
هذا العالم.
Poor and weak,
فقير وضعيف ،
the people here,
الناس هنا ،
Ignorance.
جهل.
You kept saying that
ظللت تقول ذلك
you were going to save everyone.
كنت تنوي إنقاذ الجميع.
To save everyone,
لإنقاذ الجميع ،
I think what you should really save
أعتقد أن ما يجب عليك حفظه حقًا
is your people who are easy to eat.
شعبك سهل الأكل.
You let some hunters who can't read characters
تركت بعض الصيادين الذين لا يستطيعون قراءة الشخصيات
know what righteousness is,
تعرف ما هو البر ،
To understand the rise and fall,
لفهم الصعود والسقوط ،
it's better to give them a piece of bread.
من الأفضل إعطائهم قطعة خبز.
This is called drinking poison to quench thirst.
وهذا ما يسمى بشرب السم لإرواء العطش.
You use idioms well.
أنت تستخدم التعابير بشكل جيد.
Fengchen,
فنغتشين ،
the Teacher of Justice,
يا معلم العدل
I'm invincible.
انا لا اقهر.
You have to be careful tomorrow.
عليك أن تكون حذرا غدا.
Don't lose your life.
لا تفقد حياتك.
Okay.
تمام.
Tomorrow,
الغد،
I'll take you to the Thousand Worms Sacrifice,
سآخذك إلى ذبيحة الألف دودة ،
I want you to see it with your own eyes.
أريدك أن تراها بأم عينيك.
When the barbarians meet the civilization,
عندما يلتقي البرابرة بالحضارة ،
they are so vulnerable.
هم ضعفاء جدا.
I made this specially for you.
لقد صنعت هذا خصيصا من أجلك.
It's miasma-proof medicine.
إنه دواء مضاد للالتهاب.
Tomorrow morning,
غدا صباحا،
it will be a big battle.
ستكون معركة كبيرة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
It's your Young Master who will be saved tomorrow.
سيدك الشاب هو الذي سيخلص غدًا.
You're the main force. Why don't you drink?
أنت القوة الرئيسية.  لماذا لا تشرب
You aren't manly at all. Why?
أنت لست رجولي على الإطلاق.  لماذا ا؟
I'll go down the mountain and have a look.
سأذهب إلى أسفل الجبل وألقي نظرة.
Come back and drink.
تعال واشرب.
Come back.
عد.
Drink it before you go.
اشربه قبل أن تذهب.
Look at him.
انظر اليه.
Drink it.
اشربه.
That's right,
صحيح،
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
How are things going
كيف تجري الامور
with Yan Yun and Yan Ying?
مع يان يون ويان ينغ؟
Mr. Jin, can you help us?
سيد جين ، هل يمكنك مساعدتنا؟
It depends on whether the two of them are smart or not,
يعتمد ذلك على ما إذا كان الاثنان ذكيان أم لا ،
as long as they don't fight each other again.
طالما أنهم لا يقاتلون بعضهم البعض مرة أخرى.
At this point,
عند هذه النقطة،
I can count on Xiao'e the most.
يمكنني الاعتماد على Xiao'e أكثر.
Without emotional entanglements,
بدون تشابكات عاطفية
it's the most rational.
إنه الأكثر عقلانية.
Once a person has a tie,
بمجرد أن يحصل الشخص على ربطة عنق ،
it's hard to be smart.
من الصعب أن تكون ذكيًا.
Well, I think
حسنا انا اعتقد
I'm stupid.
أنا غبي.
Aren't you stupid too?
ألست غبيًا أيضًا؟
What are you up to?
ما آخر ما توصلت اليه؟
Does it still hurt?
هل ما زال يؤلم؟
It doesn't hurt anymore.
لم يعد يؤلم.
When you recover,
عندما تتعافى ،
you guys
شباب
Do you want to go back to Ba Song,
هل تريد العودة إلى با سونغ ،
or go back to Tokyo with me?
أو العودة إلى طوكيو معي؟
I want to see my father.
اريد ان ارى والدي.
Mother,
الأم،
I've been dreaming about my father every night lately.
كنت أحلم بوالدي كل ليلة مؤخرًا.
Could you show me that pocket watch?
هل يمكن أن تريني ساعة الجيب تلك؟
I'd like to see a picture of you and father.
أود أن أرى صورة لك ولأبي.
You and father
أنت ووالدك
were so young back then.
كانوا صغارًا في ذلك الوقت.
I remember when we took this photo,
أتذكر عندما التقطنا هذه الصورة ،
there was a big flood between us,
كان هناك فيضان كبير بيننا ،
You know, before this,
كما تعلم ، قبل هذا ،
I've been living in seclusion,
كنت أعيش في عزلة ،
Every day when I look up,
كل يوم عندما أبحث ،
it's a square piece of sky
إنها قطعة مربعة من السماء
in my home,
في منزلي،
Until I met your father.
حتى قابلت والدك.
He took me around
أخذني في الجوار
to see the outside world.
لرؤية العالم الخارجي.
When he found out,
عندما اكتشف ،
I was so eager to hold a show,
كنت حريصًا جدًا على إقامة عرض ،
During the Western wedding,
خلال الزفاف الغربي ،
he took me to Hankou Concession.
أخذني إلى امتياز هانكو.
So I took the photo just now.
لذلك التقطت الصورة الآن.
I didn't know we'd run into a flood
لم أكن أعلم أننا سنواجه فيضانًا
just after we finished filming,
بعد أن انتهينا من التصوير مباشرة ،
As a result, people all over the street were running for their lives.
نتيجة لذلك ، كان الناس في جميع أنحاء الشارع يركضون للنجاة بحياتهم.
It's just the two of us
نحن فقط
who have no idea and are still walking on the street.
الذين ليس لديهم فكرة ولا يزالون يسيرون في الشارع.
Aren't you afraid at that time?
ألا تخاف في ذلك الوقت؟
Yes.
نعم.
But as if your father is by my side,
ولكن كما لو كان والدك بجانبي ،
I'm not that scared.
أنا لست خائفا.
Then what happened to you?
ثم ماذا حدث لك؟
Later,
في وقت لاحق،
later he took me back to Ba Song.
لاحقًا أعادني إلى با سونغ.
We read books together during the day,
نقرأ الكتب معًا خلال النهار ،
and at night,
وفي الليل،
Just under the night sky,
تحت سماء الليل ،
talking to each other,
نتحدث مع بعض،
Sometimes he took me to the forest,
في بعض الأحيان كان يأخذني إلى الغابة ،
and summoned those rabbits for me.
واستدعيت تلك الأرانب من أجلي.
Squirrel came to play with me,
جاء السنجاب ليلعب معي ،
it was really a time like a fairy.
لقد كان حقًا وقتًا مثل الجنية.
The Banmen Mountain Tribulation,
محنة جبل بنمن ،
all the dreams are beautiful,
كل الاحلام جميلة
In an instant,
في لحظة،
they all disappeared.
لقد اختفوا جميعا.
Mother,
الأم،
I believe father will come back one day.
أعتقد أن الأب سيعود ذات يوم.
As long as we wait until then,
طالما ننتظر حتى ذلك الحين ،
our family will still be here.
ستبقى عائلتنا هنا.
What Zerg treasure
ما الزرج كنز
or hatred secret doesn't matter anymore, right?
أو سر الكراهية لم يعد مهمًا ، أليس كذلك؟
As long as father comes back,
ما دام الأب يعود ،
as long as we're still here,
طالما أننا ما زلنا هنا ،
We can't go back to Yanying,
لا يمكننا العودة إلى Yanying ،
even if he's still here,
حتى لو كان لا يزال هنا ،
We can't go back.
لا يمكننا العودة.
At least I can't go back.
على الأقل لا يمكنني العودة.
Mother.
الأم.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
please help save Ziwu
الرجاء المساعدة في إنقاذ Ziwu
and Feng Wanchun.
و Feng Wanchun.
Because only in that way,
لأنه بهذه الطريقة فقط ،
we Zerg can work together
يمكننا العمل معًا في شركة Zerg
to find the treasure.
للعثور على الكنز.
Father said,
قال الأب ،
as long as the Zerg treasure is reopened,
طالما أعيد فتح كنز الزرج ،
He'll be back soon.
سوف يعود قريبا.
You.
أنت.
Can you help us?
هل يمكن ان تساعدنا؟
Anyway, no matter what,
على أي حال ، مهما كان الأمر ،
we can't let Fengchen Jun and the others
لا يمكننا السماح لـ Fengchen Jun والآخرين
commit evil deeds anymore, right?
بعد الآن يرتكبون أعمال شريرة ، أليس كذلك؟
Mother,
الأم،
I believe that if father is here,
أعتقد أنه إذا كان الأب هنا ،
he will agree with us.
سوف يتفق معنا.
Don't you think so?
ألا تعتقد ذلك؟